Inventory of the John H. Morse papers
Hoover Institution Archives
John H. Morse papers
1957-1973
87007
Hoover Institution Archives
4 manuscript boxes (1.6 linear feet)
Correspondence, speeches and writings, memoranda, studies, and printed matter, related to nuclear warfare strategy, questions of nuclear arms testing and disarmament, the positioning of nuclear missiles in Europe as a part of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization alliance, and the development of the neutron bomb.
Morse, John H.
Box 1-4
Shelf 64.03
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1987.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
United States deputy assistant secretary of defense for European and NATO affairs, 1970-1973.
Scope and Content of Collection
Contains correspondence, speeches and writings, memoranda, studies, research material, and printed matter related to nuclear warfare strategy, questions of nuclear arms testing and disarmament, the positioning of nuclear missiles in Europe as a part of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization alliance, Cold War armament strategies, and the development of the neutron bomb.
North Atlantic Treaty Organization.; United States. Dept. of Defense.; Arms control.; Europe--Military relations--United States.; Neutron bomb.; Nuclear weapons.; United States--Military policy.; United States--Military relations--Europe.
- 1960-1972 (Folder 1)
  - 1960-1961 (Folder 1: 1)
  - 1960-1973 (Folder 1: 2)
  - 1970-1972 (Folder 1: 3)
- Miscellaneous reading, undated (Folder 1: 4-5)
- Morse Nixon recommendation, undated (Folder 1: 6)
- 1957-1966 (Folder 1)
  - 1957-1963 (Folder 1: 7)
  - 1963-1966 (Folder 1: 8)
- Cold War armament strategy collected materials for the American-Allied colloquium in Juan-les-Pins, France, 1973 (Folder 2: 1-2)
- Edward Teller materials, 1964-1968 (Folder 2: 3)
- Department of Defense, 1970-1973, undated (Folder 2)
  - Consulting work materials, undated (Folder 2: 4)
  - Concept papers, 1970-1973 (Folder 2: 5-6)
  - International Security Affairs Strategy material, undated (Folder 2: 7-8)
- Personal chronological file, 1969-1973 (Folder 3)
  - December 1969-December 1970 (Folder 3: 1)
  - January 1971-December 1971 (Folder 3: 2)
  - January 1972 (Folder 3: 3)
  - 1973 (Folder 3: 4)
- Memos, undated (Folder 3: 5)
- National defense strategies printed material, 1969-1973 (Folder 4: 1)
- National defense issues printed material, 1969-1973 (Folder 4: 2)
- 1966-1973 (Folder 4: 3-5)
- Declassified Records, 1958-1971
  - 2015 May release of records, 1958-1971 (Box-folder 4: 6)